<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>climbing on Johannes Ehm</title>
    <link>https://www.johannesehm.de/tags/climbing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in climbing on Johannes Ehm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.johannesehm.de/tags/climbing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Klettern im Kindergarten</title>
      <link>https://www.johannesehm.de/mountaineering/220905-climbing-in-kindergarten/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.johannesehm.de/mountaineering/220905-climbing-in-kindergarten/</guid>
      <description>Kindergarten is a wall in the Stie Alm Kessel at Brauneck. Last week, on 4.9.2022, we went to the Kindergarten for some climbing. The Brauneck can be reached via Lenggries in the south of munich. In order to reach the Stie Alm Kessel a walk of 1.5 hours with an elevation gain of about 950 meters in heigth is needed. As an alternative it is also possible to take the cable car and walk around 20 minutes from the cable car station to the Stie Alm Kessel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing in Fr채nkische Schweiz</title>
      <link>https://www.johannesehm.de/mountaineering/220814-climbing-in-fraenkische-schweiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.johannesehm.de/mountaineering/220814-climbing-in-fraenkische-schweiz/</guid>
      <description>Climbing in the Fr채nkische Schweiz is an extraordinary rediscovery of Franken, the place where I did grew up. The Fr채nkische Schweiz is an area within Bavaria inbetween the triangle Nurnberg, Bamberg and Bayreuth which is known on the one hand for beer and on the other hand for climbing. The Fr채nkische Schweiz is a part of the Frankenjura which is an extraordinary geological region: beautiful valleys with beautiful streams, dense forests and high rising rocks shape the area where some of the nicest but also hardest climbing walls in Bavaria can be found.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
